Design document: 1945
-------------
◊Description◊
-------------
1945 is a vertical scrolling shooter. The player controls an airplane, and shoots
at incoming enemies to score points.  Running into the enemies will reduce a
health bar and when the bar expires, a life is lost. When all lives are lost, 
the game ends, and a high score table will appear. 
----------
◊Controls◊
----------
Movement(up, down, left, right): Arrow keys
Fire weapon: Spacebar
	-pressing the button once will fire it once, holding it will 
	 continuously fire bullets at 2 bullets per second.

Alpha Controls:
R key - Activates "Rapid Fire" for 30 seconds. Rapid fire increases the 
        rate of fire when the Spacebar is held to 6 bullets per second.
        A timer is currently displayed in the top left corner of the window, 
        and counts in steps, down from 900. (game goes at 30 steps/second)
------------
◊Challenges◊
------------
Enemies:
-Alpha plan-
      - Enemies will start easy, simply coming down from the top of the screen
	in small numbers.  As the game progresses, they will increase in
 	number, and become harder to deal with. Starting with enemies firing
 	straight down, and then enemies with directional bullets, fired
	directly at the player, but still avoidable.

-Beta plan-
      - After learning the Alpha functions, will learn to use paths and 
	time lines, so enemies can appear in groups and patterns, instead 
	of eventually becoming one big mass that leads to certain death. 
	Once the aforementioned is learned, will slowly add the other features.
        
------------------
◊Planned Features◊
------------------
- Multiple Weapon modes, which will be activated by Item drops from enemies: 
  - Rapid Fire:
    will function the same as it does in the Alpha, except it will be activated 
    by an item instead of a button press.
  
  - Dual, Triple, and Quadruple bullets:
    A "POW" item will drop, and picking it up will increase the bullets fired
    in one shot. Bullets will be lined up horizontally along the front of 
    the player's plane.  First pickup will activate Dual shot, 2nd activates 
    Triple Shot, and 3rd activates Quad shot.  Any picked up after the 3rd one 
    will earn the player 1000 points.
    
  - Spread Fire:
    When picked up, 2 more bullets will shoot diagonally at 45 degrees on each
    side of the first horizontal one. If a second one is picked up, bullets 
    will shoot horizontally from each side of the plane. A third will make 
    bullets shoot out the back end of the plane.  Any picked up after the 3rd
    is active will earn the player 1000 points.
	
  -NOTE- If the player dies while "POW'd up", initially he will go down 1 level 
  of power. An option that will be investigated is that the power level
  will go down completely after death, and if the player has lives left,
  POW's will scatter from the player's death site, enough to earn the player 
  up to one less level from where they were at when they died.  After the 
  player respawns, they will have a limited time before the dropped POW items
  disappear.

- After the basic enemy engine is redesigned to use paths and time lines,
  will look into designing individual levels with bosses, in different 
  locations, and designing new enemies to fit the location, so you
  are not always flying over the sea.  Example might be a new level fying 
  over land, so perhaps tanks for a new enemy. New enemies may also be bigger,
  and take more than one shot to destroy.

- Additional Plane designs to fly:
  As of now there is only one plane design that the player flies - the 
  P-38 Lightning.  Plans are to include from 3 to possibly 6 planes, 
  of varying statistics: Health, Speed(how fast the plane moves around the 
  level), and Power(how effective the weapon is against a formidable enemy, 
  or a boss). One new design has already been drawn for a sprite, but not 
  implemented: a B-26 Marauder.  Other ideas are the Mosquito, and the Shinden.
  